<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Blog by John Doe]]></title><description><![CDATA[Pellentesque odio nisi, euismod in, pharetra a, ultricies in, diam. Sed arcu.]]></description><link>https://lumen.netlify.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:02:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The Future is Already Here, but it's Not Evenly Distributed]]></title><link>https://lumen.netlify.com/posts//posts/future-is-already-here/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lumen.netlify.com/posts//posts/future-is-already-here/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 0202 18:06:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The future is already here, it’s just not evenly distributed yet. When I read this &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fortelabs/status/1383278931713789955&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;tweet by Tiago Forte&lt;/a&gt;, I coudn’t help but write this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read it as : Some folks got lucky, early in thier childhood and got sucked into the whirlpool of internet culture. They are able to see how the future looks like very clearly. Or at least what the 3/4 likely pathways are. Simply because it’s prototyped right in front of their eyes, in the town-squares of the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not because these folks are ‘smarter’ in any way (some are, yes). They’re just mostly better exposed to these mega-trends simply because of their unique vantage point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eg. ‘Fortnite’ playing  pre-teens using in-game collaboration tooling are without their knowledge helping chart the blueprint for ERP software of the 2025 to 2030s. ‘Discord’, the collaboration tool that’s massively gaining popularity has its origins in ‘kids just playing online games’. Discord’s story is testimony. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These individuals are struggling to communicate with their peer network what they are seeing to get others onboard too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a good idea for others to get others onboard simply because these are world changing mega trends that are one of the most powerful forces on the planet at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first decided to be a part of this, I had no fucking clue how big this was going to be. I did it, back in 1999/2000 types simply because it was a lot of fun to fiddle around with. Also, this ‘Internet’ thing was disrupting my thriving paper porn business, and I was forced to pay attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also lead to my choosing to pursue higher studies in ‘Engineering, because this new ‘Internet’ thing was so so interesting. No one told me that Computer Science was what I had to take to be truly part of this, and that ‘Electronics’ was not the foundational layer. Nevertheless, the syllabi for everything was 20 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s so frustrating when we’re unable to articulate to someone outside this circle as to what we’re seeing. The beauty, grandness and the myriad possibilities. Most often my incoherence and artless articulations end up pulling the others into the vortex of my own confusion, rather than helping them also see clearly, everything that’s happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incoherence of it all is not just the result of individual failing, it’s also because of how new, fragile, vague, unstructured and uncertain these ideas and prototypes are. Ideas and perspectives that are so new and orthogonal, even the best minds of the world are just toying with it like toddlers fiddling around with a new toy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outsiders, when they apply their mental models that worked with legacy systems are frustrated when their old mental models are utterly useless to ‘box’, ‘label’ and ‘explain’ these new systems, often causing them to give up midway, developing an aversion in the process. They then return to the comfort of their existing functional systems - mature, nearly done with all the iterations, scaled up, thriving and ‘socially accepted’. The majority of the loopholes have been closed, mostly with inefficient human interventions. However, these  legacy systems reek of design flaws and scaling flaws (size scaling and time scaling) that are simply ‘unfixable’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;footnote&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote&quot; aria-label=&quot;footnote permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Footnote&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s something that can’t be left unsaid about the makers of this new future. There’s something to be said about fallibilism mindset most of the makers of the new systems carry. There’s infinite creative freedom in its inherent inconclusiveness. A few deep but dispassionate thinkers understand this.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Love for the word Grok]]></title><link>https://lumen.netlify.com/posts//posts/love-for-the-word-grok/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lumen.netlify.com/posts//posts/love-for-the-word-grok/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I fell in love with the word Grok when I first read it in Heinlein’s novel : Stranger in a Strange Land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word sort of conveys what I wish to do with the world around me; to ‘truly, deeply understand what’s going and be able to hold that understanding inside my head’; to put it shortly, ‘to grok it’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to translate it to my mother tongue, Malayalam, the word that came closest in meaning was the word ‘ഗ്രഹിക്കുക’. (Grahikkuka; to grok)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kinda eerie that both Martian and Malayalam were using similar syllables :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/grok&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Merriam Webster definition of ‘Grok’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grok \ ˈgräk  \ : to understand profoundly and intuitively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grok may be the only English word that derives from Martian. Yes, we do mean the language of the planet Mars. No, we’re not getting spacey; we’ve just ventured into the realm of science fiction. “Grok” was introduced in Robert A. Heinlein’s 1961 science fiction novel Stranger in a Strange Land. The book’s main character, Valentine Michael Smith, is a Martian-raised human who comes to earth as an adult, bringing with him words from his native tongue and a unique perspective on the strange, strange ways of earthlings. “Grok” was quickly adopted by the youth culture of America and has since peppered the vernacular of those who grok it, from the hippies of the ’60s to the computerniks of the ’90s.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scientific Explorer vs. Scientific Consumer]]></title><link>https://lumen.netlify.com/posts//posts/scientific-explorer-vs-scientific-consumer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lumen.netlify.com/posts//posts/scientific-explorer-vs-scientific-consumer</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there’s any point entirely basing our personal opinions on knowledge that has been completely proven, tested, verified and peer-reviewed. You’re just a consumer of scientific knowledge then, not a scientific explorer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re not making brave new assumptions about the world you live in, using faculties like feelings, emotions, intuition, keen observation, curiosity, deductive logic, mental modelling, common sense etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s totally worth risking your reputation to come up with a new premise that can be up for mockery, ridicule, criticism, questioning, peer review, experimentation and testing. That’s the only way new science and new knowledge can emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make you sure don’t forget the experimentation and testing part. Self-deception tends to be scarily high among Scientific explorers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the knowledge and the collaboration that internet provides nowadays, the number of people who can afford to and actually be full-time scientific explorers and use the scientific method in their domain is higher than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have a scientific explorer state of mind, it’s not worth your time being just a consumer.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>