<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gautham]]></title><description><![CDATA[I can’t help but write. It’s the only way I grok.]]></description><link>https://g3mo.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 19:58:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Love for the word Grok]]></title><link>https://g3mo.github.io/posts/love-for-the-word-grok/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://g3mo.github.io/posts/love-for-the-word-grok/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I fell in love with the word Grok when I first read it in Heinlein’s novel : Stranger in a Strange Land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word sort of conveys what I wish to do with the world around me; to ‘truly, deeply understand what’s going and be able to hold that understanding inside my head’; to put it shortly, ‘to grok it’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to translate it to my mother tongue, Malayalam, the word that came closest in meaning was the word ‘ഗ്രഹിക്കുക’. (Grahikkuka; to grok)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kinda eerie that both Martian and Malayalam were using similar syllables :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/grok&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Merriam Webster definition of ‘Grok’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;grok \ ˈgräk  \ : to understand profoundly and intuitively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grok may be the only English word that derives from Martian. Yes, we do mean the language of the planet Mars. No, we’re not getting spacey; we’ve just ventured into the realm of science fiction. “Grok” was introduced in Robert A. Heinlein’s 1961 science fiction novel Stranger in a Strange Land. The book’s main character, Valentine Michael Smith, is a Martian-raised human who comes to earth as an adult, bringing with him words from his native tongue and a unique perspective on the strange, strange ways of earthlings. “Grok” was quickly adopted by the youth culture of America and has since peppered the vernacular of those who grok it, from the hippies of the ’60s to the computerniks of the ’90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 29 October 2019&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Scientific Explorer vs. Scientific Consumer]]></title><link>https://g3mo.github.io/posts/scientific-explorer-vs-scientific-consumer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://g3mo.github.io/posts/scientific-explorer-vs-scientific-consumer</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there’s any point entirely basing our personal opinions on knowledge that has been completely proven, tested, verified and peer-reviewed. You’re just a consumer of scientific knowledge then, not a scientific explorer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re not making brave new assumptions about the world you live in, using faculties like feelings, emotions, intuition, keen observation, curiosity, deductive logic, mental modelling, common sense etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s totally worth risking your reputation to come up with a new premise that can be up for mockery, ridicule, criticism, questioning, peer review, experimentation and testing. That’s the only way new science and new knowledge can emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just make you sure don’t forget the experimentation and testing part. Self-deception is scarily high among Scientific explorers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the knowledge and the collaboration that internet provides nowadays, the number of people who can afford to and actually be full-time scientific explorers and use the scientific method in their domain is higher that ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have a bent of scientific explorer state of mind, it’s not worth your time being just a consumer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Update: 29 October 2019&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>